MICHAEL BAUMER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

615-749-7777



MeesterBaumer@mac.com



github.com/meesterbaumer



linkedin.com/in/meesterbaumer/



www.MBaumer.tech

ABOUT:

During my nearly 20 years in the retail industry, I had the opportunity to work in every role from associate to upper level management. While I love leading teams and developing talent, my true passion was always the problem solving aspects of my role. After supporting the corporate office with numerous tech projects and watching changing dynamics in the retail sector, I knew it was time to follow my heart and learn development so I could do what I love full-time.

PROJECTS:

VauLT | Front End Capstone Single page web app built using React.

VauLT allows numismatists to catalog and organizing their ever growing collection of coins and precious metals. This allows them to not only visualize their collection but to additionally render collection value along with profit by coin and collection.

- Allows individual management on a per user basis.
- Full CRUD functionality allowing the addition of users, collections and individual metal storage.
- Collection value and profit derived from API calls to the Metals-API.
- implemented the use of Cloudinary to handle image upload and storage.
- github.com/meesterbaumer/VauLT
- youtu.be/UNdwYdpXOuw

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE:

Software Developer

Nashville Software School | 2020 - 2021 Intensive six-month, full-time remote software development program. The curriculum teaches the skills and technologies required to become a full-stack software developer.

Course inclusive of the following:

- HTML, CSS and JavaScript for the front end along with Python and Django for the server side.
- Created full CRUD single page applications utilizing both Javascript(ES6) and React.
- Projects completed in both individual and group settings using Zoom as a communications platform.
- Source code version control via GitHub including utilization of GitHub projects in addition to issue tracking.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

RETAIL OPERATIONS GENERAL MANAGER

Finnleys Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

Responsible for providing direction and management for the profitable and efficient day-to-day operations of the company.

- Managed Operations for the organization on both the storeline and corporate side of the business
- Led all aspects of storeline performance to include: Hiring, Talent development, Merchandising, Loss Prevention, Payroll and Human Resources.
- Led the IT initiative for all stores and the corporate
- Reported to and worked directly with the owner of the company on all current and future strategic initiatives.
- implemented online review cycle for 2020
- implemented storeline/corporate budget tracking for all store and corporate expenses.

MICHAEL BAUMER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

615-749-7777



MeesterBaumer@mac.com



github.com/meesterbaumer



linkedin.com/in/meesterbaumer/

PROJECTS (CONT.)

CycleShare | Final Capstone Single page web application allowing the travelling cyclist the ability to search for and secure a reservation on a bike. Users can additionally manage the bikes in their garage as well as review other users on the platform.

- Full CRUD application.
- Built using React for the front end and Python/Django on the back end.
- youtu.be/3RePRBruRaO
- github.com/meesterbaumer/cycleshareclient

Holiday Road | Group Project Single page application designed to allow the end user to build a National Park travel itinerary.

- Full CRUD application.
- Implemented weather forecasts to match the selected park
- Made API calls to the National Park Services API.
- Allowed users to name and save itineraries.
- github.com/NSS-Day-Cohort-42/holidayroad-wailing-worms

TECH STACK

- HTML, CSS3, JS
- JSON
- React
- Git/GitHub
- VS Code

- Python
- Django
- SQLite
- Postman
- Slack
- Zoom

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

DISTRICT MANAGER

Aeropostale OPCO | May 2006 - October 2019

Analyzed profitability and ensured effective operations of 16-20 retail locations across Tennessee, Alabama. Kentucky and Georgia. Acted as a liaison between the corporate office and the store-line teams.

- Recruited and developed a team of 65 Managers and over 250 associates.
- Provided both in person and remote leadership by way of in-store visits, Email and conference calls with store teams.
- Supported the full implementation of Dayforce (Work-Force Management software) by supporting the corporate office in analysis, testing, training/ development, and ongoing support.
- Developed an online tracking tool to support staffing projections along with managing a live dashboard to visualize hiring across the district and region.
- Created numerous business tools to streamline operations, data entry and business analysis. All of which were used by District Managers across the organization.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

Nashville Software School 2020 - 2021

- -Graduated with a Full Stack Software
- Development certificate.
- -Graduated Jan. 2021